

Patrick Michl

Senior Data Scientist | Al Engineer | Mathematician



PERSONAL

Contact Floringasse 5, 69117 Heidelberg, DE

Phone: +49 177 85 44 151 EMail: patrick.michl@gmail.com

Legal POB/Date-: 93309 Kelheim, DE at 05/19/1982

Nationality: German Marital status: Married

Online Professional profile: <u>LinkedIn</u>

Research profile: ORCid | Heidelberg University

Software development: <u>GitHub | PyPI</u> Blog/Talks: <u>Frootlab | SlideShare</u>

Certificates: Credly | Coursera | Scrum.org



ABOUT

I spent the most part of my professional and educational lifetime by shaping my experience and expertise in AI, machine learning, software development and network technologies. During this process I gained domain specific insights into different industries comprising manufacturing (engineering, shop floor and office) as well as finance and pharma (research). I identify myself as a passionate mathematician, obsessive software developer and convinced AI enthusiast.



EDUCATION

Ruprecht-Karls-University

Heidelberg, 2006 - 2018

Mathematics Diploma: Grade 1.4 / GPA 3.6, with specialization in statistics, machine learning and differential geometry. Subsidiary subjects: Theoretical physics, applied computer sciences and systems biology. Fundamental research in machine learning and systems biology with honored diploma thesis: Principal Manifold based Correlation Analysis

Ostbayerische Technische Hochschule

Regensburg, 2003 - 2006

Applied mathematics with specialization in graph theory, optimization and operations-research. Subsidiary subjects: Relational database management, software development and economics. Internship semester: Development / implementation of a graph-based optimization algorithm / software for automated machine translation.



LANGUAGES

German: Native | English: Fluent | French: Basic | Irish: Basic



EXPERIENCE

amprela GmbH, Senior Data Scientist

Mannheim, 05/2021 - present

Process mining, enterprise data modeling and digitalization projects from inception to project management (Scrum), implementation and operation.

reboot GmbH, Data Scientist

Mannheim, 03/2020 - 06/2021

Al driven shop floor automation, business analytics, database development and digitalization projects comprising predictive maintenance and RPA

Freelance Data Scientist

Heidelberg, 03/2018 - 02/2020

Consulting in data warehousing, cloud computing, data analytics- and digitalization projects in the Rhine-Neckar metropolitan area.

Frootlab Smart Analytics, Founder

Heidelberg, 05/2016 - Present

Founder, software architect and consultant for a next generation low code software framework for automated collaborative computing.

Ruprecht-Karls-University

06/2008 - 02/2014, *Institute for Mathematics*, Systemadministrator: Unix administration, database administration and network security

05/2012 - 07/2012, *Institute for Molecular Biotechnology*, Research Assistant: Deep-learning-based gene expression analysis

10/2008 - 03/2009, *Institute for Computer Sciences*, Lecture Assistant: Applied CS at software engineering research group

DKFZ, Research Assistant

Heidelberg, 12/2012 - 01/2014

Research in deep-learning-based gene regulation analysis with application to breast cancer and GBM at network modeling research group

IHK, Technical Writer

Regenstauf, 10/2011 - 09/2012

Authoring of the textbook "Netzwerktechnik", NET(TE)1, ArtNr. 02303, for the vocational education of electrical engineers in germany.



SKILLS

Machine Learning | Statistics | AI | Data Visualization and Presentation Statistical Programming (Python, SAS, R, Matlab) | Business Analytics Predictive Maintenance | Process Mining, RPA | Network Technology DB Dev (SQL, noSQL) | Cloud Dev (Docker, Kubernetes, Azure, Spark) Web Dev (TypeScript, Angular, PHP; REST) | Administration (Debian) IT Project Management (Scrum)